Finding Aid for the Lawrence Clark Powell Papers LSC.0229
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Publications File
  - 1963
    - Supplementary Reading List. In Mexico: a Sunset Discovery Book. Menlo Park, California: Land Book Company, 1963. (Box 55)
    - A Traveler's Notebook on Reading. In New York Times (Western Edition), June 14, 1963. (Box 55)
  - 1964
    - Aldous Huxley, 1894-1963; addresses at a memorial meeting held in the School of Library Service,, by Lawrence Clark Powell, Robert R. Kirsch, and Jacob Zeitlin. Los Angeles, University of California, February 27, 1964 1964. (Box 56)
      Printed in the Netherlands at Gouda by Koch & Knuttel N.V. as a keepsake for the Class of 1964, School of Library Service, UCLA.
    - Charles K. Adams. Hoja Volante, no.78 [Obituary]., November 1964 (Box 56)
    - The education of an educator. In Library Journal (vol.89, no.3), February 1, 1964. (Box 56)
    - Harold Haines Clark, 1878-1964. Santa Monica, printed by William M. Cheney, [Eulogy]. (Box 56)
    - In search of spring. In Southwest Review (vol.49, no.1), Winter 1964. (Box 56)
    - In search of spring. Printed by Richard Hoffman's students at Los Angeles State College, 1964. (Box 56)
    - Leaves of grass, poems of Walt Whitman, selected and with a foreword by Lawrence Clark Powell. New York, Thomas Y. Crowell Company, 1964. (Box 56)
      (See also box 74)
    - The little package, pages on literature and landscape from a traveling bookman's life. (Box 56)
      (See boxes 58-59, & 73)
    - The lure of Californiana. In California Librarian (vol.25, no.3), July 1964. (Box 56)
    - The lure of Californiana. In Quarterly News Letter of the Book Club of California (vol.29, no.4), Fall 1964. (Box 56)
    - [Preface to] the Magpie Press Typographical Cookbook. Los Angeles, 1964. (Box 56)
    - Make mine a small one. In New York Times Book Review (Christmas Issue), December 6, 1964. (Box 56)
    - Speaking of books: in the words of Kenneth Rexroth. In New York Times Book Review (vol.69, no.46), November 22, 1964. (Box 56)
    - The three L's. Los Angeles: The Press in the Gatehouse, 1964. (Box 56)
    - Viva Wagner! Remarks by Lawrence Clark Powell at the Memorial Award Dinner given by the California Historical Society at San Francisco on Los Angeles: The Press in the Gatehouse, September 25, 1964. 1964. (Box 56)
    - William Alexander Jackson, 1905-1964. Hoja Volante (no.78), [Obituary]., November 1964 (Box 56)
    - A world that's wide and wonderful New York Times Book Review, Paperback Book Section, Supplement to the Western Edition., January 6, 1964 (Box 56)
    - The way west. In Rodgers Library Notes (vol.13, no.1-4), October 1963, January, April and July 1964. (Box 56)
    - The writer in an automated world. A discussion by Eric Hoffer, Robert Kirsch, and Kenneth Rexroth. Moderator, Lawrence Clark Powell. California Librarian (vol.25, no.2), April 1964. (Box 56)
      [Lightly edited transcript of the second general session of the Annual Conference, California Library Association, San Francisco, December 11, 1963].
- Southwestern Book Trails
  - Manuscripts and Typescripts
    - Southwestern Book Trails, A Reader's Guide to Arizona, New Mexico, and adjacent lands., (Holograph manuscript, [236] leaves) (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Draft no.1, with typescript title page, dedications, and first 7 leaves.
    - Southwestern Book Trails, A Reader's Guide to the Heartland of New Mexico and Arizona., (Typescript, [112] leaves) (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Draft no.2 with holograph corrections.
    - Southwestern Book Trails, A Reader's Guide to the Heartland of New Mexico and Arizona., ([114] leaves) (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Printer's typescript with some holograph corrections.
      Also, corrections, Notes to Bill Wallace from R. Dickey (Typescript, [2] leaves).
  - Galleys and Page Proofs
    - Southwestern Book Trails, A Reader's Guide to the Heartland of New Mexico and Arizona., ([26] leaves) (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Southwestern Book Trails, A Reader's Guide to the Heartland of New Mexico and Arizona., ([68] leaves) (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Page proofs with some publisher's corrections.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Libraries of the Southwest, Outline and Reading List Compiled by Lawrence Clark Powell., (Ozalid copy, 9 leaves) (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Kino Sketches, by Ted De Grazia., ([2]pp.) (Box 57, Folder 7)
      Printed excerpts.
    - A Short Assessment, by Patricia P. Paylore., ([1]p.) (Box 57, Folder 7)
      Printed excerpt.
  - Publication
    - Southwestern Book Trails, A Reader's Guide to the Heartland of New Mexico and Arizona. Albuquerque: Horn and Wallace, 1963. (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence with various persons, 1962-1969. (Box 57, Folder 9)
- The Little Package
  - Galley Proofs and Plastic Proofs
    - The Little Package, Pages on Literature and Landscape from a Traveling Bookman's Life., ([101] leaves) (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - The Little Package, Pages on Literature and Landscape from a Traveling Bookman's Life., ([100] leaves) (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - The Little Package, Pages on Literature and Landscape from a Traveling Bookman's Life., ([100] leaves) (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - The Little Package, Pages on Literature and Landscape from a Traveling Bookman's Life., ([4] leaves) (Box 58, Folder 4)
      Galley proof with corrections, and page proof for dust jacket.
      Also, miscellaneous pages of galley proofs with publisher's and holograph corrections (Photocopy, [10] leaves).
    - The Little Package, Pages on Literature and Landscape from a Traveling Bookman's Life., ([78] leaves) (Box 58, Folder 5)
      Foundry plastic plate proofs.
    - The Little Package, Pages on Literature and Landscape from a Traveling Bookman's Life., ([78] leaves) (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript
    - The Little Package, Pages on Literature and Landscape from a Traveling Bookman's Life., (Typescript (first half, numbered leaves 1-150) [150] leaves) (Box 59, Folder 1)
      With publisher's corrections.
    - The Little Package, Pages on Literature and Landscape from a Traveling Bookman's Life., (Typescript (second half, numbered leaves 151-320) [170] leaves) (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - The Little Package, Pages on Literature and Landscape from a Traveling Bookman's Life., (Typescript, 71 leaves) (Box 59, Folder 3)
      Index and dust jacket.
  - Page Proofs
    - The Little Package, Pages on Literature and Landscape from a Traveling Bookman's Life., ([329] leaves) (Box 59, Folder 4)
      Page proofs with publisher's corrections.
  - Publication
    - The Little Package, Pages on Literature and Landscape from a Traveling Bookman's Life. Cleveland: World, 1964. (Box 59, Folder 5)
- Publications File (Continued)
  - 1965
    - Book shops. In Antiquarian Bookman (vol.36, no.23), December 6, 1965. (Box 60)
    - Down where the rockies end. In Mountain-Plains Library Quarterly (vol.10, no.3), Fall, 1965. (Box 60)
    - Great land of libraries. In ALA Bulletin (vol.59, no.7), July-August 1965. (Box 60)
    - Letters from the famous and the faceless. In New York Times Book Review (vol.70, no.19, part 1), May 9, 1965. (Box 60)
    - Make mine a small one. Peacock Press, 1965. (Box 60)
      [Reprinted from] New York Times Book Review, December 6, 1964.
    - [Forward to] The making of the Cambridge bibliography, by George Watson, 1965. (Box 60)
    - [Forward to] Milton and Clarendon, by French R. Fogle, William Andrews Clark Memorial Library, 1965. (Box 60)
    - A place of intense radiation. In New Mexico Quarterly (vol.34, no.4), Winter 1964 and 1965. (Box 60)
    - [Contributions by LCP and others] Richard Addington: an intimate portrait. Alister Kershaw, editor, 1965. (Box 60)
    - The stagecoach press. In Texas and the West. Catalogue no.32, 1965. (Box 60)
    - Strictly local. In Southern California Quarterly (vol.47, no.4), December 1965. (Box 60)
    - The three L's. In California School Libraries (vol.36, no.4), May 1965. (Box 60)
    - Tekrat ti. Uhitelké Noviny (Journal of Czech teachers), [Translated from Nine by nine from Books in my baggage]., 1965. (Box 60)
    - [Eulogy] Words spoken in memory of Ralph MacKnight Smith, 1943-1965, at a memorial service held in Santa Monica, California, March 23, 1965. (Box 60)
    - Dana, Richard Henry. Two years before the mast. In Southern California Quarterly., March 1965. (Box 60)
    - Duffus, R.L. Queen Calafia's Island (Titled: A tale of two cities). New York Times Book Review, 1965. (Box 60)
    - Speaking of books: Yeats-Wellesley letters. In New York Times Book Review (vol.70, no.13), March 28, 1965. (Box 60)
    - Waters, Frank. The man who killed the deer. In Southwest Review., Autumn 1965. (Box 60)
  - 1966-1967
    - Come hither. Edited by Lawrence Clark Powell. Los Angeles: Yeasayers Press, 1966. (Box 61)
    - First draft of essays., (Typescript, [24] leaves) (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Typescript with holograph corrections., ([31] leaves) (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Page proofs., ([41] leaves) (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Publications: Come hither! Papers in Children's Literature and Librarianship. Edited and with a preface by Lawrence Clark Powell. Los Angeles: Yeasayers Press, 1966. (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1968. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      re publication and distribution of copies.
    - [Forward to] Library Publications, by William R. Holman. Reprinted in Antiquarian Bookman., January 1966 (Box 61)
    - Musical Blood Brothers. Malibu, California: Press of the Prevailing Westerly, 1966. (Box 61)
    - [Introduction to] Report of the third decade, by Eric Gill. William Andrews Clark Memorial Library, 1956-1966 1966. (Box 61)
    - You, John Milton. Sooner Magazine (vol.38, no.3), March 1, 1966. (Box 61)
      [Reprinted from You, John Milton, an address by LCP at the University of Oklahoma Library by Mrs. George P. Livermore. January 14, 1966].
    - Bibliographers of the Golden State: Alexander Smith Taylor., 1967. (Box 61)
    - Research materials. (Box 61, Folder 1)
      re Alexander Smith Taylor.
    - Bibliographers of the Golden State, 1967. (Box 61, Folder 2)
      First and second drafts.
    - Correspondence from various persons, 1967-19??. (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - [In Memoriam] Books on the Western Hemisphere Printed Prior to 1801. Bennett and Marshall Catalog no.4, 1967. (Box 61)
    - The elements of a good librarian. In Occidental College Alumnus, Winter 1967. (Box 61)
    - From abroad. In The Calibrarian (vol.16, no.1), Winter/Spring 1967. (Box 61)
    - From Monterey to San Simeon: Jeffers, Miller, and Brother Antoninus. In Western Review., Winter 1967. (Box 61)
    - Speaking of books: The Hogan file. In New York Times Book Review, May 14, 1967. (Box 61)
  - Westways. Classics reread by LCP, 1962-1970. (Box 62, Box 63)
  - Southwest Classics reread, 1973-. (Box 82)
    (Continued from box 63)
  - 1968-1970
    - Brother Antoninus at Wesleyan. In The Tin Drum (vol.1, no.4), June 1968. (Box 64)
    - Climbing the ladder. In Library Journal (vol.93, no.1, Part 1), January 1, 1968. (Box 64)
    - A dedication to the memory of Mary Hunter Austin, 1868-1934. In Arizona and the West., 1968. (Box 64)
    - Fortune and friendship: An Autobiography. Bowker, 1968. (Box 64)
      (See boxes 70-72)
    - An interview with LCP. In Bay State Librarian (vol.57, no.3), Fall 1968. (Box 64)
    - Landscape with books. In Arizona Librarian (vol.25, no.3), Fall, 1968. (Box 64)
    - Lawrence Clark Powell: Olé Olin. In Wesleyan Library Notes (no.1), Autumn 1968. (Box 64)
    - [Original bibliography] Lawrence Durrell, a study by G.S. Fraser with a bibliography by Alan G. Thomas, 1968. (Box 64)
    - Los Angeles Bibliography. Los Angeles, a Sunset Book, 1968. (Box 64)
    - Majl Ewing, 1903-1967. Hoja Volante. (no.91), Zamorano Club, Los Angeles., February, 1968. (Box 64)
    - South from Lisbon. In Southwest Review., Spring 1968. (Box 64)
    - Bond, William H., (ed.) Records of a Bibliographer: Selected Papers of William Alexander Jackson. Journal of Library History (vol.3, no.1), [Book Review]., January 1968 (Box 64)
    - Speaking of books: Robinson Jeffers. In New York Times Book Review, October 6, 1968. (Box 64)
    - In Memory of Melba Berry Bennett, 1901-1968. One hundred copies printed for Theodore M. Lilienthal at the Ward Ritchie Press. (Box 64)
    - David A. Randall, Dukedom Large Enough. New York Times Book Review, August 31, 1969. (Box 64)
    - Box 64--Additions (Box 64)
    - The three L's. In Collectors' Institute. Comemorative brochure. Inaugural meeting, November 23, 1968. (Box 64)
      [Speech by LCP on p.2]
    - The example of Miss Edith M. Coulter. California Library Association. Keepsake no.8, (17th Coulter Lecture, sponsored by the University of California Library Schools Alumni Association, given at the California Library Association conference, San Diego,, by LCP)., 1969. October 25, 1968 (Box 64)
    - The Ella Strong Denison Library. In Scripps College Bulletin (vol.44, no.2), October 1969. (Box 64)
    - Charles Fletcher Lummis and the land of sunshine. In Westways (reprint), 1970. (Box 64)
    - John E. Goodwin, founder of the UCLA Library. An essay toward a biography. Address delivered to CLA, Library History Committee, Los Angeles., October 23, 1970.; (Typescript [carbon] 13 leaves) (Box 64)
    - Shoe on the other foot: From library administrator to user. In Wilson Library Bulletin, December 1970.; (p.384) (Box 64)
    - A tribute to Bradford Booth. In Modern Fiction Studies (vol.16, no.2), Summer 1970. (Box 64)
    - Untarnished gold, the immutable treasure. A report on a book-in-progress. Davis, University of California, 1970.. (Box 64)
- Personal Correspondence as Dean of the UCLA School Of Library Service
  (In alphabetical order)
  - A. (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - ALA Bulletin. (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, University Librarian, 1960-61. (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - B. (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - C. (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Summer Class, Projects., 1963 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - SLS 203. (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - SLS 204. (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - SLS 205. (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - SLS 208. (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - SLS 241. (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - SLS 241, Class Projects, Fall 1961. (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - SLS 241, Class Projects, Summer 1962. (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - SLS 241, Class Projects, Summer 1961. (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - SLS 298. (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Committees. (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Clarence Day Award. (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - D. (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - E. (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - F. (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - G. (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - H. (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - I. (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - J. (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - K. (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - L. (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - M. (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - N. (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - O. (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - P. (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Q. (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - R. (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Research Group. (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Ritchie, Ward. (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Rounce & Coffin. (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Roxburghe Club. (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Royalty Reports. (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - S. (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - T. (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - U. (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - V. (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - W. (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Wilson Library Bulletin. (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - X. (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Y. (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - Z. (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - Zamorano Club. (Box 68, Folder 16)
- Library Postcards Project
  - Correspondence relating to project, 1962-1966. (Box 69, Folder 1)
    Postcards are in boxes 118, 121-126.
  - Correspondence, 1967. (Box 69, Folder 2)
- LCP Speaking Engagements
  - LCP speaking schedules, 1956-1964. (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - LCP speaking regrets. Correspondence, ca. 1960-1969. (Box 69, Folder 2-3)
  - LCP invitations turned down. Correspondence, ca. 1969-1972. (Box 69, Folder 4)
- Fortune & Friendship: an Autobiography.
  - Manuscripts
    - Fortune & Friendship: an Autobiography., (Holograph manuscript in pencil, 378 leaves plus pencil notes, 9 leaves) (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Fortune & Friendship: an Autobiography., (227 leaves) (Box 70, Folder 2)
      First typed draft with holograph corrections and publishers' corrections.
    - Fortune & Friendship: an Autobiography., (Photocopy typescript, 217 leaves) (Box 70, Folder 3)
      Annotated by John Berry and colleagues at Bowker.
    - Fortune & Friendship: an Autobiography., (215 leaves) (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Galley Proofs
    - Fortune & Friendship: an Autobiography., (91 leaves) (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Fortune & Friendship: an Autobiography., (91 leaves) (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Publication
    - Fortune & Friendship: an Autobiography. Unbound publication. (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Fortune & Friendship: an Autobiography by Lawrence Clark Powell. New York/London: R.R. Bowker Company, 1968.; (xiii, 227pp.) (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Book Reviews
    - The making of a bookman. In AB Bookman's Weekly, September 23, 1968.; (p.975) (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Passionate bookman. In Library Journal, July 1968. (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - The little red package. In Hoja Volante, (no.93) [Reviewed by Tyrus Harmsen]., August 1968 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence with publisher, Bowker, 1967-1969. (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with various persons, 1968. (Box 72, Folder 2)
      [Includes printed materials and photocopies of reviews]
    - Correspondence with various persons, 1969. (Box 72, Folder 3)
      [Includes copies of reviews.]
- Correspondence re Publications
  (Most such correspondence is boxed with the files on a particular publication)
  - A Passion for Books, 1959
    (See boxes 15-16)
    - Responses from readers, 1958-January, 1959. (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Responses from readers, February-December 1959. (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Responses from readers, 1960-. (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with World Publishing Company, 1959. (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with William Targ of World Publishing Company, 1956-1962. (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous--newspaper clippings, etc. (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Poems of Walt Whitman, 1964
    (See box 56)
    - Correspondence with publisher, Thomas Y. Crowell Company, 1963-1966. (Box 74, Folder 1)
      [Includes publicity for volume and copies of reviews.]
  - The Little Package, 1964
    - Correspondence with readers, and World Publishing Company, 1963-1965. (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Bookman's Progress, 1968
    - Reviews, clippings, correspondence, 1968-1969. (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence With Publishers
    - Alfred A. Knopf, 1950-1966. (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Willaim Targ, 1959-1970. (Box 74, Folder 2)
- Libraries in the Southwest, 1955
  - Correspondence, 1953-1954. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    Preliminary drafts, etc. planning for Conference on Libraries in the Southwest.
  - Correspondence, drafts and typescript copies of conference participants' presentations, etc., January-April 1955. (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, typescripts, etc., May 1955-. (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Patricia Peylore's file on the conference. (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Publications After the Conference:
    - Mexico challenges the future. Joint meeting of the Southwest Conference and the California Library Association, Southern District. Occidental College [Program]., April 15 and 16, 1955. (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Reynolds, J.E. Low barometer in the Southwest. Reprinted from Library Journal, October 1, 1955.; (3pp.) (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Libraries in the Southwest. In UCLA Occasional Papers (no.3). Reissued, 1961.; (45pp.) (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Libraries in the Southwest. Their Growth - Strengths - Needs. In UCLA Occasional Papers (no.3), 1955.; (70pp.) (Box 75, Folder 5)
- Correspondents By Postcard
  - Postcards from various people in various places, to LCP. (Box 76)
    (Does no include library postcards)
- Various Correspondents (Continued)
  - Browning, Robert
    - The ring and the book., 1959-1961. (Box 77)
      Correspondence re publication of G. Connes' translation.
    - L'anneau et le livre. Translated by Georges Connes. Paris, 1959. (Box 77)
  - Grauer, Ben
    - Correspondence with LCP, 1946-1968. (Box 77)
  - Hinchcliff, William Emerson
    - Correspondence with LCP, 1961-July 1963. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with LCP, August 1963-1965. (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Hubbs, Stanley
    - Poetry and prose, ca. 1964.; (Photocopy and typescript-carbon) (Box 78)
  - Maclennan, Kenneth C.
    - Correspondence with LCP, 1949-1952. (Box 78)
  - Templin, Ernest H.
    - Sonnets on the death of a sixteen year old son., (Typescripts) (Box 78)
  - Robinson, W.W.
    - W.W. Robinson. Reminders of Spain in Los Angeles. In Ford Times, May 1962. (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Letters to LCP, 1949-1968. (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Letters to LCP and others, 1964-1965. (Box 78, Folder 3)
      re Robinson's book Los Angeles.
    - Letters from LCP to W.W., Robinson, 1947-1952. (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Letters from W.W. Robinson, 1969-1971. (Box 78, Folder 5)
      re The Malibu and Powell's introduction to Jimmie Hicks' W. W. Robinson: a biography and bibliography..
    - Correspondence, September 1972. (Box 78, Folder 6)
      re death of W.W. Robinson and manuscript drafts of LCP's eulogy, given September 6, 1972.
  - Yelland, Edna (Mrs. W.R.)
    - Letters to LCP, 1964. (Box 78)
  - Zornes, Milford
    - Letters to LCP and miscellaneous printed material, 1947-1952. (Box 78)
- Lawrence Clark Powell Tape Recordings, 1971-197?
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  [See also] box 132
  - Dark spring, bright spring. Talk in the College of Education, University of Arizona, Tucson., May 11, 1971.; (1 reel [7 in.] 3.75 i.p.s) (Box 79)
    [See box 80 for transcript].
  - Dedication of the addition to the Mary Norton Clapp Library. Occidental College., January 20, 1971.; (1 reel [5 in.] 3.75 i.p.s)
    [see box 80 for transcript; c.f. box 38].
  - Los Angeles Library Association. Annual tribute to Los Angeles authors--honoring Fay and Lawrence Clark Powell., Alexandria hotel., April 19, 1971; (1 reel [7 in.])
- Publications File (Continued)
  - 1971-1972
    - [Book review] California local history: A bibliography and union list of library holdings. Stanford University Press, 1970. In: College and Research Libraries, (vol.32, no.1)., January 1971; (p.48) (Box 80)
    - Dark spring, bright spring. Talk given at the University of Arizona, Tuscon, May 11, 1971.; (Typescript, photocopy) (Box 80)
      [See box 79 for tape recording of talk]
    - In memoriam: Paul Jordan Smith. [Eulogy delivered, June 21, 1971.; (Typescript, photocopy) (Box 80)
    - Library addition dedicated. Occidental College Alumnus, vol.53, no.3 [excerpts from LCP's Remarks on the occasion of the dedication....]., February 1971. (Box 80)
    - [Forward to] Poems of Walt Whitman: Leaves of Grass. selected by Lawrence Clark Powell. New York: Crowell, 1971.; (Paperback edition) (Box 80)
    - Remarks on the occasion of the dedication of the addition to the Mary Norton Clapp Library. Occidental College, January 20, 1971. (Box 80)
    - The three H's. Los Angeles: Press in the gatehouse, 1971. (Box 80)
    - Three loves have I. In AB Bookman's Yearbook (Part 1), [reprint of part of Randolph G. Adams memorial lecture, given in the William L. Clements Library, University of Michigan, ]., 1971. 1953; (p.29) (Box 80)